jonbarron.org 2019-06-03

# Website Privacy Notice | Baseline of Health

**Read our company website privacy notice which is compliant with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

Last Updated on May 25th, 2018

## **1\. INTRODUCTION**

Baseline of Health Foundation (“Website”) is committed to protecting your privacy.

### **Privacy and Security**

We respect your right to privacy. Therefore, we do not sell any names or any information to a mailing list, or third party. We only use your information to help us process your orders and better serve you.

### **Security**

Our website uses Secure Sockets Layering (SSL) to encrypt your personal information.

This privacy notice provides you with details of how we collect and process your personal data through your use of our site owned and operated by Baseline of Health Foundation– (jonbarron.org), including any information you may provide through our site, sign up to any of our newsletters or take part in a survey.

By providing us with your data, you warrant to us that you are 18 years or age or older.

## **2\. WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data means any information capable of identifying an individual. It does not include anonymized data.

We may collect and maintain any personal information you enter on our Website or provide to us in some other manner. For example, when you sign up for a newsletter or participate in a survey..

We may process certain types of personal data about you as follows:

  * Customer biographical information such as name, and email address
  * For your security, we do not accept orders or store credit card numbers.

Marketing and Communications Data may include your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us.

### Sensitive Data

We do not collect any Sensitive Data about you. Sensitive data refers to data that includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, genetic and biometric data. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We may also collect certain non-personally identifiable information via the Website, such as Website usage activity and preferences, also known as profile or demographic data, the IP address assigned to the computer visiting the site, the type of browser used by a visitor, the web page from which you came, and the operating system running the user’s connections to the service. This data is not linked to you. This helps us make the Website as useful as possible.

The Website uses small files called “cookies,” which are pieces of information that your browser receives from websites and stores on your computer’s hard drive.  Use of this technology helps us recognize you when you visit our website and thus allows us to personalize your online experience. For example, by storing cookies on your hard drive, you’ll return to a specific website with the same settings you used on a previous visit. If you choose, you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can manually delete individual or all of the cookies on your computer by following your browser’s help file directions. However, if your browser is set to reject cookies or you manually delete cookies, you may have some trouble accessing and using some of the pages and features that are currently on our Website, or that we may put on our Website in the future. For more information on our cookie policy, see paragraph 12 below.

## **3\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We collect data about you through a variety of different methods including:

  * Direct interactions: You may provide data by filling in forms on our site (or otherwise) or by communicating with us by post, phone, email or otherwise, including when you: 
    * subscribe to our newsletters;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey;
    * or give us feedback.
  * Technical Data from the following parties: 
    * analytics providers such as Google Analytics based outside the EU;

## **4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when legally permitted. The most common uses of your personal data are:

  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
  * The information we receive allows us to tailor our newsletters and blogs and improve your browsing experience, making your experience more informative, easier, and more enjoyable. It also enables us to customize the content and layout of our pages, notify you about updates to our Website, and provide you with health related information.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal ground for processing your personal data, other than in relation to sending communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw consent at any time by clicking on our Unsubscribe link at the bottom of our email communications.

### Purposes for processing your personal data

Set out below is a description of the ways we intend to use your personal data and the legal grounds on which we will process such data. We have also explained what our legitimate interests are where relevant.

We may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground, depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please submit a support ticket by emailing: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) If you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new subscriber | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

| Performance of a contract with you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services  
  
To enable you to partake in a competition or complete a survey | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Financial

d) Transaction

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business  
  
To administer and protect our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganization or group restructuring exercise 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant content to you and measure and understand the effectiveness of our emails and website content | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy  
To use data analytics to improve our website and subscriber/visitor relationships and experiences | (a) Technical 

(b) Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about content that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

| Necessary for our legitimate interests to develop our products/services and grow our business  
  
## **5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above:

  * With our support team and management.
  * Service providers who provide IT and system administration services as well as email service providers.

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

## **6\. DATA SECURITY**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## **7\. DATA RETENTION**

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

## **8\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include the right to:

Request access to your personal data. Request correction of your personal data. Request erasure of your personal data. Object to processing of your personal data. Request restriction of processing your personal data. Request transfer of your personal data. Right to withdraw consent. You can see more about these rights at:

[https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/.](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us by submitting a support ticket by emailing: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## **9.THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

## **10\. CHILDREN  **

The Baseline of Health Foundation Website is not directed to children under the age of 18, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18 years old.

## **11\. CONTACT US**

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy and/or the practices of this web site, please contact us at: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

By using the Baseline of Health Foundation Website, you signify that you have read, understand, and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. We may change this Policy from time to time, and the changes are effective upon posting. Please review our Privacy Policy regularly. Your continued use of the Website after changes are posted constitutes your agreement to the changes. If you do not agree to the changes, please discontinue your use of the Website.

The Baseline of Health Foundation is the data controller and we are responsible for your personal data (referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).

If you are not happy with any aspect of how we collect and use your data, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk)](http://surefire.clickfunnels.com/www.ico.org.uk). We should be grateful if you would contact us first if you do have a complaint so that we can try to resolve it for you.

It is very important that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. Please let us know if at any time your personal information changes by submitting a support ticket by emailing: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

## **12\. COOKIE POLICY**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly.

### What’s a cookie?

  * A “cookie” is a piece of information that is stored on your computer’s hard drive and which records how you move your way around a website so that, when you revisit that website, it can present tailored options based on the information stored about your last visit. Cookies can also be used to analyze traffic and for advertising and marketing purposes.
  * Cookies are used by nearly all websites and do not harm your system.
  * If you want to check or change what types of cookies you accept, this can usually be altered within your browser settings. You can block cookies at any time by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

### How do we use cookies?

  * We use cookies to track your use of our website. This enables us to understand how you use the site and track any patterns with regards how you are using our website. This helps us to develop and improve our website as well as products and / or services in response to what you might need or want.

### Cookies are either:

  * Session cookies: these are only stored on your computer during your web session and are automatically deleted when you close your browser – they usually store an anonymous session ID allowing you to browse a website without having to log in to each page but they do not collect any personal data from your computer; or
  * Persistent cookies: a persistent cookie is stored as a file on your computer and it remains there when you close your web browser. The cookie can be read by the website that created it when you visit that website again. [We use persistent cookies for Google Analytics.] [We also use Facebook Pixels]

### Cookies can also be categorized as follows:

  * Strictly necessary cookies: These cookies are essential to enable you to use the website effectively and therefore cannot be turned off. Without these cookies, the services available to you on our website cannot be provided. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you have been on the internet.
  * Performance cookies: These cookies enable us to monitor and improve the performance of our website. For example, they allow us to count visits, identify traffic sources and see which parts of the site are most popular.
  * Functionality cookies: These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make and provide enhanced features. For instance, we may be able to provide you with news or updates relevant to the services you use. They may also be used to provide services you have requested such as viewing a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect is usually anonymized.
